Hello everyone and welcome back to English
Pod. My name is Marco and my name is
Catherine and today we have an
advanced media level lesson so that's the
very highest of our levels. Right and
we're gonna be talking about a very
popular tradition in North America
and Thanksgiving dinner. Okay so thanks
giving is a very special holiday for
Americans and Canadians also celebrate it
and different dates right Canadians have
it on a different date. Exactly I'm not
sure the Canadian date is but American
celebrated at the end of November the day
changes every year because it's a Thursday
but we usually have the day off from
work or school and we all eat together
and celebrate the year and celebrate
the harvest and celebrate our
families and friends. So this tradition of
Thanksgiving what do you
commemorate or what do you celebrate?
Well we actually celebrate the first
harvest that the pilgrims had when they were
right off the boat in New England so
that's the eastern part of America. These
people had come from England and
they were trying to find a new land and a
new life and they ended up in the
Massachusetts area and they didn't know how
to farm. They didn't know how to work
the land and so the Native Americans who
were living there at the time helped
them out, helped them grow corn, helped
them find out how to use the land in
a productive way and so when that first
harvest happened everyone was able
to grow, it's actually a year after they
arrived, everyone was able to grow
corn and food and crops and then they all
shared a meal together to celebrate
this wonderful occasion. Wow and it
actually helped them survive the winter
because most of the pilgrims, most of
the settlers, they died during the
first winter and so this was a really great
great thing for them. Wow that's
really interesting an interesting aspect of
history and why this is celebrated
mostly as you say in North America and
Canada and that's why many other
countries don't really have it but it's a
popular get-together and what
you usually have is a turkey right?
Exactly so turkey is a very big bird and
they go go go go go go and they have that
kind of really red-long kind of thing
on their necks and big tail or big tail
feathers and they're delicious but
the funny thing is about turkey that
there's a chemical in it that makes
you very sleepy well not a couple there's
a protein in it that makes you very really.
I didn't know that. So the joke is that
after you eat dinner on Thanksgiving
everyone falls asleep on the sofa well
Thanksgiving meals in the United
States are very very big they're very
elaborate right? You're not only a
turkey but you have pumpkin pie and you
have mashed potatoes and gravy and
just like a table full of food. Exactly and
it's a way to celebrate well to give
thanks for all the things that you have
and so we like to give light to cook
a lot of food to celebrate that and
they're all fall foods. So squash
pumpkin potatoes things like that.
Alright so we have a dialogue here so it's
just that it's a guy who is preparing a
turkey dinner and also preparing
pumpkin pie but he's doing it in a very
peculiar way so why don't we listen to
the dialogue and then we'll come back
and just talk a little bit about
the different terms that he used.
Hello everyone and welcome back to
our show. Today we are going to learn
how to cook the perfect Thanksgiving
turkey. I will share a secret that I have
kept for over 30 years on how to cook
the perfect most mouthwatering juiciest
turkey in the world. Let's get started.
First of all we must bring out our key
ingredient whiskey. You see the grains
used to make whiskey along with the alcohol
brings out the flavor of the turkey meat.
Let's pour one cup of whiskey on the
turkey and serve yourself a cup as well.
Cheers. That's good 12 year whiskey right
there. Okay back to our turkey preheat
your oven to 475 degrees Fahrenheit. Now
have another cup of whiskey. Now
that the oven is hot we place our bird on a
rack inside a roasting pan. Let's add
some whiskey to give it some extra flavor
and let's have another cup. That hit
the spot. There we go. We can leave it in
there for the next 45 minutes. In the
meantime let's have another sip of whiskey
and start with our delicious pumpkin pie.
Lightly whisk together two eggs and the
extra yolk in a large bowl. Once that's
ready we can put sugar spices such as
cloves, grated nutmeg and cinnamon with
some cream and dark rum into a saucepan.
Slowly bring up to simmering points during
occasionally. Now you may notice that
we are using some dark rum in this pie.
This is because the richness of the
pumpkin is beautifully enhanced by
the dark rum. So to celebrate this great
occasion for yourself a glass. Cheers.
Now that we have finished with the filling
let's make the pie for 45 to 15 minutes
until the filling has puffed up around
the edges and the center is almost set.
All done. A cup of rum to celebrate the
completion of this great Thanksgiving
dinner. After waiting for an hour and
having a couple of drinks is time to
check on our turkey. Take the turkey out of
the oven. Pick the turkey off of the
ground. Don't worry it will add flavor to
this recipe. Now also remove the pie
from the oven and serve while still hot.
Cheers and happy Thanksgiving!
All right we're back so I think this is
gonna be one great Thanksgiving dinner
for him. Oh my gosh and talking about
this is making me so hungry. This always
happens when we have food lessons. What
about do you have any family members who
actually drink a little bit too much during
Thanksgiving? Yes and I won't say that.
All right so as he was preparing the
Thanksgiving dinner he mentioned a
couple of things. For example a mouth
watering turkey. Mouth watering so this is a
way to say appetizing. You know
when you see something delicious on TV
and your mouth starts to water your
salivating that means that your your brain is
telling you that you want to eat it. Right
and so your mouth starts to water so we
say that something that's very appetizing
something that looks like it will
taste very very good. It's mouth watering.
All right so he was preparing a mouth
watering turkey. So moving on he mentioned
that he had a key ingredient for his
turkey and it was whiskey. Not
only whiskey but 12-year whiskey.
Okay so the thing about whiskey is that
oftentimes on the label of a bottle they'll
advertise how old the whiskey is
because you pay more for older whiskey.
They have better taste in many cases. Well
in this case it's a 12-year whiskey. That
means that it was stored in a cast for
12 years to let it age and then they sell
it after 12 years and so that's the
special ingredient. That's the special
ingredient. 12-year whiskey and well
he not only put it on the turkey but also
he had a couple of drinks himself and
in one of those he mentioned that hit the
spot. That hit the spot. What spot?
The spot. Okay so this is a really common
phrase in English that we used to
say that something is very satisfying.
Mm-hmm so I hit the spot. Not only for
drinks right? No you could use it for food or
anything really. So in this case I could
say oh I was so hungry that sandwich
really hit the spot. I really needed to eat
right now and that sandwich was perfect.
That was perfect. All right so that
hit the spot. Now when he referred to
the turkey in one occasion he said
we place our bird on a rack. All right so
what's a bird and what's what's
what's the rack? Okay so this is a this is
really interesting. We talk about the
turkey oftentimes when we're making
commercials or talking about recipes
as the bird. So you want to take out the
bird and you want to open the packaging.
So the bird is the turkey. Turkey is a
kind of bird. You can say this about
chicken as well because it's another kind
of bird but this is a kind of a colloquial
term in cooking for whatever bird
you're cooking. Right okay and when
you're placing it on a rack what's a rack?
Okay so in our ovens an oven is it's a
kitchen item appliance that you have
that heats up food but it's not like a
microwave it's much stronger and so
inside there are metal bars. Mm-hmm. We
don't have they're like shells but they're
open and so these metal bars are
called a rack. Okay so you put the turkey
in the oven on the rack. Right you
can't put it on the on the base of the oven
because then it would burn up. Exactly
and you you don't have a shelf because that
would be a problem. All right and well
moving on on the instructions when he
was preparing the pumpkin pie he told
us to lightly whisk together two eggs so
we have a verb here to whisk to whisk
so that's not only a verb but a noun
as well right? All
right. It's an instrument.
Exactly and this
is a verb we often
use with eggs so to whisk eggs you
can also whisk like sauce for a salad so
like a salad dressing but it's a way
that we stir something and so often times
we have an instrument called a whisk
that that's not like a fork it actually
looks kind of funny it's got bars on eggs.
Like wire that kind of make a circle
exactly and they are very thin wires
and it you usually stir very very very
quickly it's especially if you have
eggs this will break up the egg and
it becomes kind of like foamy. Foamy
yeah to make like an omelet for example.
Exactly so to whisk is a kind of
it's a way to stir. Okay and then he
mentioned is something greedy and such
as sugar, spices and grated nutmeg so what
is this for grated nutmeg or what
an adjective grated? Exactly so this
adjective grated means that
it also kind of weighs a cut-up
something and so you often hear that
the term grated cheese that means not a
big chunk of cheese but we push it
against a board to get little pieces of
it to fall off and that's called grated
cheese and so in this case we have grated
nutmeg that means that it's been kind of
the nutmeg comes in in very small pieces.
Yeah pieces and we we're breaking
it down. Alright very good and he
also mentioned something about bringing
the the sauce to a simmering point.
What is that simmering point?
Okay simmering point is a time when you're
cooking where the liquid goes from
being calm to being very agitated
and moving but it's not boiling right?
No boiling means you have big bubbles
right like boiling water but
simmering is where it's kind of little
bottle there's a little bit of action
on the surface of the liquid but it's
not boiling it's in the
middle between flat and calm
and agitated and boiling. Okay so
that's the simmering point very good
and that's pretty much all of the of
the interesting phrases in the dialogue.
There are a lot more but we
don't really have time to cover that
huge amount of rich vocabulary so why don't
we listen to this dialogue one last time?
Hello everyone and
welcome back to our show.
Today we are going to learn how to
cook the perfect Thanksgiving turkey.
I will share a secret that I have kept
for over 30 years on how to cook the
perfect most mouthwatering
juiciest turkey in the world.
Let's get started. First of all we must
bring out our key ingredient whiskey.
You see the grains used to make
whiskey along with the alcohol
brings out the flavor of the turkey meat.
Let's pour one cup of whiskey on the
turkey and serve yourself a cup as well.
Cheers!
That's good 12-year whiskey right there.
Okay back to our turkey.
Preheat your oven to
475 degrees Fahrenheit.
Now have another cup of whiskey.
Now that the oven is hot we place
our bird on a rack inside a roasting pan.
Let's add some whiskey to give it some
extra flavor and let's have another cup.
That hit the spot. There we go. We can
leave it in there for the next 45 minutes.
In the meantime let's
have another sip of
whiskey and start with
our delicious pumpkin pie.
Lightly whisk together
two eggs and the
extra yolk in a large
bowl. Once that's ready
we can put sugar spices
such as cloves, grated
nutmeg and cinnamon
with some cream and dark
rum into a saucepan. Slowly bring up
to simmering points during occasionally.
Now you may notice that we are
using some dark rum in this pie.
This is because the richness of the pumpkin
is beautifully enhanced by the dark rum.
So to celebrate this great
occasion for yourself a glass. Cheers!
Now that we have finished with the filling
let's bake the pie for 45 to 15 minutes
until the filling has puffed up around
the edges and the center is almost set.
All done. A cup of
rum to celebrate the
completion of this great
Thanksgiving dinner.
After waiting for an
hour and having a couple
of drinks is time to
check on our turkey.
Take the turkey out of the oven.
Pick the turkey off of the ground. Don't
worry it will add flavor to this recipe.
Now also remove the pie
from the oven and serve
while still hot. Cheers
and happy Thanksgiving!
All right we're back
so Thanksgiving dinner
really popular Catherine
have you ever cooked
or are you into the
whole Thanksgiving feast?
I'm very into it. It's my
favorite holiday in America.
Mostly because everyone
gets to celebrate it it's
not religious so you
don't have to worry about
other people not
celebrating it or not knowing
what to do and it's also
a celebration about family
and food and so it's
just it's a wonderful
experience to have
Thanksgiving because you're with
everybody and we always
say in America that if
someone doesn't have a
place to go on Thanksgiving you
shouldn't invite
them to your house.
So it's very inviting and warm
holiday and I love cooking
and I love being in the
kitchen and I love having
people in the house
cooking and so yeah I've
definitely been part of
the cooking side of things.
Now in many in many
movies they kind of mock
this holiday because it's
a time where everyone
gets together as you
say no matter religion,
creator or race and that
also causes for a lot of
family members to get
together and argue and have
discussions about
politics or talk about family
problems and stuff like that
so what do you think of that?
Well I think it's an
exaggeration but it happens
people get very stressed
out during the holidays
they call it the holidays
because this is beginning
where you have
Thanksgiving and then later
Christmas but I personally
don't have experience
with that really on
Thanksgiving because it's such a
happy holiday for us so
and in my family arguments
about politics and
history and all that is very
encouraged and so it's
just a part of the holiday
where we have we have
you know one person at the
table who says this and
the other person says
this and you're all
drinking and it's it's fun
all right all right very
good so if you guys have
any other questions or
doubts about this holiday
because as we say it's
very common in North
America and Canada you can
come to our website englishpot.
com and if you have
any other questions
or suggestions you can
leave those there as well.
We look forward to hearing
what you have to say and
happy Thanksgiving. Happy
Thanksgiving. Bye everyone.